Guide to the Jerome Moross Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Jerome Moross Papers,
1924-2000
Moross, Jerome, 1913-1983.
62 linear ft (ca.7,900 items in 49 boxes & 42 oversize folders).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078363
Biographical Note
American composer of film scores, concert works, and music for ballet and theater. He died in 1983.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscript music scores, copies of scores, playscripts, scenarios, watercolor drawings and other stage designs, contracts, legal papers, programs, clippings and other printed materials, microfilms, records, tape recordings, and photographs. Among Moross's work are the musical play, "The Golden Apple"(1954), dance music for "Ballet Ballads"(1945) and for "Frankie and Johnny"(1938), the film score for "The Big Country"(1958) and for "The Cardinal"(1963), and his Symphony No. 1 (1943). There are some financial papers and production records for the staging of his works. Among the cataloged correspondents are Aaron Copland, Agnes George De Mille, Ned Rorem, Virgil Thomson, and Thornton Wilder.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 4 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Series
Series III: Works by Jerome Moross
SeriesIV: Miscellaneous items
Subjects
Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Catton, Bruce, 1899-1978.; Clemens, Cyril, 1902-; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Corwin, Norman, 1910-; De Mille, Agnes.; Evans, Maurice, 1901-1989.; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966.; Mancici, Henry.; Martin, Mary, 1913-1990.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Robbins, Jerome.; Rorem, Ned, 1923-; Thompson, Randall, 1899-1984.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.; Vidal, Gore, 1925-; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; Ballets--Piano scores.; Ballets--Scores.; Motion picture music--United States.; Music--United States--20th century.; Musicals--United States--20th century.; Operas--Scores.; Orchestral music--United States--20th century.; Radio music--United States.; Songs--United States--20th century.; Television music--United States.; Advertisements.; Announcements.; Audio cassettes.; Audio tapes.; Charts.; Compact disks.; Contracts.; Design drawings.; Drafts (literary).; Financial documents and records.; Hymns.; Interviews.; Librettos.; Manuscripts (literary).; Musical scores.; Notes.; Outlines.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Photonegatives.; Playbills.; Posters.; Programs.; Reviews.; Scores.; Scripts.; Sheet music.; Songs.; Tickets.; Videocassettes.; Watercolor drawings.; Watercolor paintings.; Composers--United States.; Musicians--United States.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1984 Papers Tarjan, Susanna Moross Gift
09/10/1991 M-91-09-10 Music scores Tarjan, Susanna Moross Gift
11/11/1991 M-91-11-11 Compact disk, tape cassette, & transcript. Tarjan, Susanna Moross Gift
05/07/1992 M-92-05-07 Two orchestral scores Tarjan, Susanna M. Gift
07/17/1992 M-92-07-17 Photocopies of 6 letters to A. Copland Library of Congress Gift
04/--/1993 M-93-04 Score for American Pattern Tarjan, Susanna Moross Gift
06/30/1993 M-93-06-30 2 scores & a CD Tarjan, S.M. Gift
02/21/1994 M-94-02-21 Music score Tarjan, S.M. Gift
03/07/1995 M-95-03-07 Henry Cowell letter Tarjan, Susanna Gift
05/23/1995 M-95-05-23 Parts & corrections for Gentlemen, Be Seated. Tarjan, Susanna Gift
07/28/1995 M-95-07-28 Moross-Palmer correspondence Tarjan, Susanna Gift
04/13/1996 M-96-04-13 Parts for Biguine. Tarjan, Susanna Gift
04/17/1996 M-96-04-17 Scores & script for The Golden Apple. Tarjan, Susanna Gift
09/06/1998 M-98-09-06 Plaque & J. Robbins telegram Tarjan, Susanna Gift
Gift of Mrs Susanna Moross Tarjan, 1984, 1987, 1990-1996, & 1998-2000.
Gift of the Library of Congress, 1992.
Selected Related Material at Columbia
Reminiscences of Jerome Moross: Oral History, 1982 Columbia Center for Oral History.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Antheil, George To Jerome and Hazel Moross, Hollywood, 14 March 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalyn To Hazel Aframs Moross, Washington, [1977-1980], (4 Christmas Cards) (Box 1)
    [With envelopes]
  - Catton, Bruce To Jerome Moross, New York, 23 September 1963, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Clemens, Cyril To Jerome Moross, Kirkwood, MO, 27 May 1970, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Copland, Aaron To Jerome Moross, Peekskill, NY & New York, NY, [n.d.] & 10 Nov 1940-7 Nov 1944, (2 pages a.l.s., 3 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Corwin, Norman To Jerome Moross, v.p., 23 April 1958-15 Dec 58, (6 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With copies of related letters.]
  - De Mille, Agnes George To Jerome Moross, [New York], 21 Jan 1952 through April 1952, (2 pages t.l.s., 1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Evans, Maurice To Hazel Aframs Moross, [n.p.], 12 July 1965, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred To Jerome Moross, New York, 5 July 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Mancini, Henry To Jerome Moross, Hollywood, CA, 19 Dec 1966, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Martin, Mary To Jerome Moross, [n.p], [n.d.], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Miller, Henry To Jerome Moross, Big Sur, CA, 2 Aug 1944, (1 p.p.c.) (Box 1)
  - Jerome Moross To Aaron Copland, Pacific Palisades & Los Angeles, CA, 1942-1944, (2 pages a.l.s., 4 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [Xerox copies. Original letters housed in the Copland Collection, Music Division, Library of Congress. Gift of the Library of Congress, 17 July 1992]
  - Robbins, Jerome To Jerome Moross, New York, 6 Nov 1944, (1 telegram) (Box 1)
  - Rorem, Ned To Jerome Moross, [n.p.] & New York, [n.d.] & [Oct 1973]-[Feb 1977], (2 a.p.c.s., 1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Thompson, Randall To Jerome Moross, Princeton, NJ, 18 June 1948, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With envelope]
  - Thomson, Virgil To Jerome Moross, New York, 18 Sept [n.y.]; 8 Oct 1979-1 June 1982, (2 pages a.l.s., 1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [One with envelope]
  - Vidal, Gore To Jerome and Hazel Moross, Beverly Hills, CA, 26 March 1968, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Wilder, Thornton To Jerome Moross, Edgarton, MA, 28 Sept 1967, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With envelope.]
- Series II: Arranged Series
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence
    - A-J, v.p., 1937-1982, (12 folders) (Box 1)
    - Federal Theatre Project Letters, v.p., 1938-1939, (1 folder) (Box 1)
    - Fisher, Thomas Hart Letters, telegrams, documents, memos, contracts., v.p., 1939-1953, (1 folder) (Box 1)
      [See also Page, Ruth.]
    - Fitelson and Mayers Letters, receipts, documents., v.p., 1944-1962, (1 folder) (Box 1)
    - K-M, v.p., [1937-1982], (8 folders) (Box 2)
    - Kroll Agency, Lucy, New York, [1947-1956], (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Kroll Agency, Lucy, New York, [1957-1959], (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Kroll Agency, Lucy, New York, [1960-1962], (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Kroll Agency, Lucy, New York, [1963-1982], (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Latouche, John Treville, [v.p.], 1943-1944, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - M-Z, [v.p.], 1937-1982, (21 folders) (Box 3)
    - To Hazel A. Moross, v.p., 1948-1953; 1956-1959, (7 folders) (Box 3)
    - Page, Ruth, v.p., [n.d.];1938-1958, (1 folder) (Box 3)
      [See also Fisher, Thomas Hart.]
    - Palmer, Christopher, v.p., 1973-1978, (1 folder) (Box 3)
      [Gift 1995-1999]
    - Palmer, Christopher, v.p., 1973-1978, (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Regarding Moross work: "Sorry Wrong Number.", v.p., 1972-1980, (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Olympia Brewing Company Regarding Moross work: "Tumwater Music.", v.p., 1965-1968, (1 folder) (Box 3)
    - Unidentified Correspondence., v.p., 1949-1979, (1 folder) (Box 3)
  - Subseries II.2: Financial Papers
    - Miscellaneous items: Receipts, check stubs, money orders, bank statements, dog license, apartment lease, insurance policies, expense reports., 1949-1981, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Account book, 1949-1981, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - American Society of Composers, Authors, & Publishers (A.S.C.A.P.) Correspondence, check stubs., 1949-1981, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Payroll statements., 1956-1960, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Royalty statements: A.S.C.A.P; Tams-Witmark Music Library, Inc.; others, [v.p.], 1954-1976, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Chappell & Co., Inc. Royalty statements., New York, 1951-1978, (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Taxes., v.p., 1950-1961, (1 folder) (Box 4)
  - Subseries II.3: Interviews and Biographical Notices
    - c.v.; 3 copies of 2 p., October 1958, (6 pages) (Box 5)
    - Mike Snell c.v., New York, 2 April 1978, (1 copy) (Box 5)
    - Frank Herbert Interview transcript., New York, 2 February 1964, (4 pages, 2 copies) (Box 5)
    - Gerald Pratley Canadian Broadcast Corp. Interview transcript., Toronto, Ontario, 01 January 1966, (12 pages) (Box 5)
    - Credits and listings from "International Who's Who and Who's Who in Amerian Theatre.", (2 pages, 2 pamphlets) (Box 5)
    - Vivian Perlis Oral History Research Office "Charles Ives Remembered" interview: 1) Recorded copy. 2) Transcript. 3) Article., New York, 19 September1969, (1 cassette, 22 pages, 3 pages) (Box 5)
  - Subseries II.4: Music Scores by Others
    - George Antheil Scores inscribed to Moross by composer: 1) "Five Songs 1919-1920" for soprano and piano. COS COB Press, New York, 1934. 2) Second Sonata "The Airplane" for piano. New Music, New York, 1931., New York, 1932 (inscription), (10 pages bd., 12 pages bd.) (Box 5)
    - Bucharoff, Simon Inscribed to Moross by composer: "The Four Freedoms," lyrics and music. Pacific Music Sales, Hollywood, CA, 1943., (7 pages bd.) (Box 5)
    - Chabrier, Emmanuel Score inscribed by Harold Schonberg: "Trois Valses Romantiques" for 2 pianos. Enoch & Cie., Paris., December 1976 (inscription), (47 pages bd.) (Box 5)
      [Mold damage]
    - Copland, Aaron Photocopies of scores in nonsequential order. Includes "Our Town.", (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Herrmann, Bernard Score inscribed to Moross by composer: "Moby Dick." Cantata for male chorus, soloists, and orchestra. Novello & Co., LTD., 10 February 1972 (inscription), (69 pages bd.) (Box 5)
    - Robinson, Earl Photocopies and ozalid copies of scores., (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Spialek, Hans Score inscribed to Moross by composer: "The Tall City." Suite for Orchestra. Harms, Inc., New York. 1933 (inscription), (122 pages bd.) (Box 5)
  - Subseries II.5: Photographs and Portraits
    - Photographs of Ives Centennial Celebration., University of Miami, 1976, (3 photographs) (Box 5)
    - Moross, Jerome Head shots, 1976, (2 photographs (10x8)) (Box 5)
    - Mathers, Don and Princess Livingston Signed and inscribed to Jerome and Hazel Moross., (1 photograph (10x8)) (Box 5)
    - Moross and unidentified woman with cello., (13 photographs (4x5)) (Box 5)
    - Moross, Jerome U.S. Passport with 4 extra passport photographs., 17 September1948, (1 passport) (Box 5)
    - Moross, Jerome Publicity photographs and contact sheets., (39 photographs (10x8)) (Box 5)
    - Lerman, Leo Inscribed and signed to Moross and Hazel Moross., 30 August 1952, (1 photograph (14x11)) (Box 5)
    - Charcol drawing. Moross head shot (adult years) with cigarette. Signed "PAV", 1989, (1 drawing (47 x 40.5 cm.)) (Box 235)
      [Gift 1999]
    - Tinted photograph. Moross full length (childhood years), domed oval., 1989, (1 photograph (50 x 35 cm.)) (Box 235)
    - Oil portrait. Moross full length (childhood years). Note: Artist's rendering of previous photograph., (1 painting (50.5 x 40 cm.)) (Box 235)
  - Subseries II.6: Biographical Mementos
    - Newspaper clippings: includes public school graduation at age 10 and obituaries., 1924-2000, (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Periodicals; clippings regarding Moross., n.d.; 1934-1979, (5 items) (Box 5)
    - Newspaper clippings-miscellaneous subjects; geographical list of League of Composers., (1 folder) (Box 5)
    - Stern, Eric and Tommy Krasker Songbook Series at Joe's Pub. Flyer: "A Tribute to Jerome Moross"; 2 copies of 1 p., New York, 28 February 2000, (2 pages) (Box 5)
      [Gift 2000]
- Series III: Works by Jerome Moross
  - Subseries III.1: Adventures of Huckleberry Finn
    See also compact disc: "Valley of Gwangi."(Box 47)
    - Orchestral score: photocopy., 1960, (156 pages bd.) (Box 6)
      [Motion Picture]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript, signed. 1960, (144 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 43)
    - Orchestral score, piano reduction: photocopy., (156 pages) (Box 43)
    - Microfilm. "Huckleberry Finn.", (1 box/reel) (Box 40)
  - Subseries III.2: American Pattern
    - Programs, newspaper clippings., n.d.; 1934-1938, (3 programs, ?? pages) (Box 6)
      [ Ballet]
  - Subseries III.3: American Saga
    - Doris Humphrey, Charles Weidman Dance Group Programs., Guild Theatre, New York, 1936, (3 programs) (Box 6)
  - Subseries III.4: Americo Vaspuccio
    - Typescript texts in Latin and English, (57 pages) (Box 6)
  - Subseries III.5: Awaken My Love, Awaken
    - 1) Vocal score for two voices and guitar: ozalid copy. 2) Vocal score: reverse copy on thin sheets. 2) Royalty statements., 1951 copyright, (2 pages, 4 pages, 3 items ) (Box 6)
      [Song]
  - Subseries III.6: Baby
    - Score for string quartet: manuscript in ink on thin sheets., 1939 copyright, (16 pages ) (Box 6)
  - Subseries III.7: Ballet
    - 1) Clippings. 2) Programs. The New School for Social Research, NY (3) and The New Chamber Orchestra, NY (5)., 1933, (? pages, 8 items) (Box 6 [COPIES])
  - Subseries III.8: Ballet Ballads
    - Financial records: statements, expense sheets, check stubs for several productions., (1 folder) (Box 6)
    - Kurt E. Wolff Financial papers., California, 1950-1951, (1 folder) (Box 7)
    - Typewritten notes., (6 pages) (Box 7)
    - To Jerome Moross Opening night telegrams., 8 May 1948-17 May 1948, (18 telegrams) (Box 7)
    - Production photographs and head shots., (53 photographs (8 x 10), 4 contact sheets) (Box 7)
    - To Jerome Moross and Hazel Moross Signed photograph from "Ruthanna and Frank.", (1 photograph (8 x 10)) (Box 7)
    - Informal cast photographs/snapshots, (6 photographs (5 x 3.5), 6 negatives ) (Box 7)
    - Programs and playbills., (40 items) (Box 7)
    - Publicity: press releases and production notices., n.d.; 1948-1950, (1 folder, ) (Box 8)
    - Newspaper and periodical clippings., n.d.; entry in process., (1 folder, ) (Box 8 [COPIES])
    - Chappell & Co., Publisher Score: "I've Got Me" (song)., 1948 copyright, (7 pages, ) (Box 8)
    - Chappell & Co., Publisher Score: "My Yellow Flower" (song)., 1948 copyright, (5 pages, ) (Box 8)
    - Chappell & Co., Publisher Score: "Ridin' on the Breeze" (song)., 1948 copyright, (5 pages, ) (Box 8)
    - Stage designs: "Susannah and Elders"; "Willy the Weeper," "Willy Alternative"; "Dave Crockett," "Dave Crockett Alternative.", (5 blueprints, ) (Box 8)
    - Vocal score "Susannah and the Elders": 1) Manuscript on thin sheets; nonsequential order. 2) Ozalid copy; binding removed., 29 Jan 1940; 1944, (83 pages, 52 pages) (Box 9)
    - Vocal score "Susannah and the Elders": ozalid copy; binding removed., 1944 copyright, (52 pages) (Box 236)
    - Orchestral score "Susannah and the Elders": manuscript on thin sheets., (85 pages) (Box 9)
    - Score for two pianos "Susannah and the Elders": ozalid copy; 2 copies., (27 pages, 27 pages; bd.) (Box 236)
    - Harry Aspruer Watercolor stage design "Susannah and the Elders." Inscribed by artist to Moross., 1, (painting with mat (15 x 20 in.) ) (Box 236)
    - Master score (70 parts) "Susannah and the Elders"; manuscript in ink., (1 folder a.ms.s.) (Box 9)
      [Gift 1995]
    - Scores for two pianos "Susannah and the Elders," "Willie the Weeper," and "The Eccentricities of Davey Crockett": ozalid copy., (145 pages, bd., ) (Box 9)
    - Vocal score "Susannah and the Elders" "Willie the Weeper," "The Eccentricities of Davey Crockett": 1) Published version. 2) Negative photostat of pages 68-69., 1949, (210 pages, bd., 2 pages) (Box 9)
    - Orchestral score "Willie the Weeper": manuscript on thin sheets., (25 pages a.ms.s., ) (Box 9)
    - Orchestral score "Willie the Weeper": manuscript on thin sheets., (220 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 236)
    - Orchestral score "Willie the Weeper": reduced transparencies on ozalid., (220 pages) (Box 236)
    - Score (22 Parts)"Willie the Weeper": manuscript on transparencies., (340 pages a.ms.s., ) (Box 9)
    - Score for two pianos "Willie the Weeper": manuscript in pencil., (52 pages a.ms.s., ) (Box 9)
    - Score for two pianos "Willie the Weeper": ozalid copies (2 copies)., (52 pages, 52 pages bd.) (Box 237)
    - Vocal score "Willie the Weeper": manuscript on thin sheets., 1945 copyright, (68 pages a.ms.s., ) (Box 9)
    - Vocal score "Willie the Weeper": ozalid copy., (68 pages) (Box 237)
    - Score for two pianos "The Eccentricities of Davy Crockett": manuscript., (66 pages) (Box 10)
    - Vocal score "The Eccentricities of Davy Crockett": ozalid copy; broken binding., (66 pages) (Box 237)
    - Vocal score "The Eccentricities of Davy Crockett": manuscript on thin sheets., 1946 copyright, (83 pages) (Box 10)
    - Score for two pianos "Riding Hood Revisited": manuscript., (63 pages) (Box 10)
    - Score for two pianos "Riding Hood Revisited": ozalid copy; 3 copies of 63 p., (3 vol.) (Box 10)
    - "Riding Hood Revisited": manuscript on thin sheets., (79 pages) (Box 10)
    - Vocal score "Riding Hood Revisited": ozalid copy; broken binding., (79 pages bd.) (Box 237)
    - Vocal score "Riding Hood Revisited": ozalid copy., (79 pages) (Box 10)
    - Microfilm: "Willie the Weeper." 1 reel; loose., (1 box) (Box 40)
    - Tape recording: "1. Susanna. 2. Willie. 3. Davy Crockett.", Los Angeles, 1950, (1 cassette) (Box 41)
    - Tape recording. "Legend Inside.", 20 October 1950, (1 box/reel) (Box 41)
    - Tape recording. "Susanna," "Davy Crockett, Part I," "Davy Crockett, Part II," "Three Dances from the Last Judgement.", (1 box/reel) (Box 41)
    - Tape recording. "The Last Judgement (piano reduction)," "Willie the Weeper.", (1 box/reel) (Box 41)
    - Records: 1) "Davy Crockett, Part I" and "Davy Crockett, Part II." 2) "Susanna" and "Willie the Weeper." 3) "Oh Baby, Gee Baby," "I've Got Me," "Yellow Flower," and "Riding on the Breeze.", (3 discs) (Box 42)
    - Score (19 Parts): "The Eccentricities of Davy Crockett.", (509 pages) (Box 48)
  - Subseries III.9: Banjo
    Written by Louis Moreau Gottschalk; arranged by Moross
    - Score for two pianos: manuscript with corresponding newspaper clippings., n.d.; 1935, (16 pages, 2 pages) (Box 10)
  - Subseries III.10: Bears
    - Score for two pianos; manuscript sketches in pencil., (19 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 10)
  - Subseries III.11: Big Country
    - Manuscript: reduced ozalid negatives., 1958, (25 pages) (Box 10)
    - Score (film sketches): 1) Manuscript. 2) Ozalid copy., 1958, (174 pages, 174 pages) (Box 10)
    - Vocal score "Another Day, Another Sunset": published version., 1958 copyright, (5 pages) (Box 10)
      [Lyrics by Morty Neff and Jack Lewis.]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in hand of Bernard L. Mayers and others. 1) Reel 1, Part 1: "Main Title"; 22 p. 2) Reel 1, Part 2: "Julie's House"; 18 p. 3) Reel 2, Part 1: "The Welcoming"; 31 p. 4) Reel 2, Part 2: "The Hazing"; 13 p. 5) Reel 2, Part 3: "Courtin' Time"; 15 p., 1958, (6 folios) (Box 238)
      [Full score: 665 pages in 46 folios]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in hand of Bernard L. Mayers and others. 6) Reel 3, Part 1: "The Terrill Ranch"; 9 p. 7) Reel 3, Part 2: "Old Thunder"; 16 p. 8) Reel 4, Part 1: "Breakfast Scene"; 13 p. 9) Reel 4, Part 2: "The Raid"; 31 p. 10) Reel 4, Part 2 (revised); 16 p. 11) Reel 4, Part 2A: "The Raid" (continued); 14 p. 12) Reel 5, Part 1: "McKay's Decision"; 10 p. 13) Reel 5, Part 2: "The Capture"; 15 p., 1958, (7 folios) (Box 238)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in hand of Bernard L. Mayers and others. 14) Reel 6, Part 1: "McKay's Triumph"; 11 p. 15) Reel 6, Part 2: "Major Terrill's Party"; 14 p. 16) Reel 6, Part 2A: "Major Terrill's Party" (continued); 9 p. 17) Reel 7, Part 1: "Waltz"; 28 p. 18) Reel 7, Parts 2 and 3: "Polka"; 7 p. and Part 2, "alternate ending"; 1 p. 19) Reel 7, Part 4: "Night in Blanco County"; 4 p. 20) Reel 8, Part 1: "McKay's Ride"; 8 p. 21) Reel 8, Part 1A: "McKay is Missing"; 11 p. 22) Reel 8, Part 1B; 16 p. 23) Reel 9, Part 1: "Waiting"; 2 p. 24) Reel 9, Part 2: "Horror Stories"; 10 p. 25) Reel 9, Part 3: "The Big Muddy"; 14 p. 26) Reel 10, Part 1: "Still Waiting"; 12 p. 27) Reel 10, Part 2: "McKay Alone"; 10 p. 28) Reel 10, Part 3: "Night at Ladder Ranch"; 5 p., 1958, (15 folios) (Box 239)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in hand of Bernard L. Mayers and others. 29) Reel 11, Part 1: "The Fight"; 17 p. 30) Reel 12, Part 1: "The Cattle at the River"; 22 p. 31) Reel 13, Part 1: "Pat's Mistake"; 10 p. 32) Reel 13, Part 2: "Buck Comes for Julia"; 9 p. 33) Reel 14, Part 1: "The Abduction"; 8 p. 34) Reel 15, Part 1: "The Captive"; 8 p. 35) Reel 15, Part 2 (revised): "The Attempted Rape"; 9 p. 36) Reel 15, Part 2 (new): "The Attempted Rape"; 17 p., 1958, (8 folios) (Box 239)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in hand of Bernard L. Mayers and others. 37) Reel 16, Part 1: "The War Party Gathers"; 22 p. 38) Reel 16, Part 1 (new). 25 p. 39) Reel 17, Part 1: "McKay in Blanco Canyon." 27 p. 40) Reel 18, Part 1: "Jim and Julie"; 2 p. 41) Reel 18, Part 2: "The Major Alone"; 14 p. 42) Reel 19, Part 1: "The Duel"; 4 p. 43) Reel 19, Part 2: "The Death of Buck Hennessy"; 11 p. 44) Reel 19, Part 3 and Reel 20, Part 1: "Ambush in Blanco Canyon"; 30 p. 45) Reel 20, Part 2: "The Stalking"; 8 p. 46) Reel 20, Part 3: End Title; 12 p., 1958, (10 folios) (Box 240)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets in pencil; signed, 1958, (144 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 241)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy., 1958, (144 pages bd.) (Box 241)
    - Programs: Royal Philharmonic Orchestra with Elmer Bernstein; Long Beach Symphony (CA) with letter from conductor John Green; Mantovani and his Concert Orchestra (Lincoln Center, NY)., v.p., n.d.; 1966-67; 1982, (4 programs) (Box 10)
    - Plaque: Academy Award Nomination for Best Music Score., Los Angeles, 1958, (1 folder, 1 framed plaque) (Box 241)
      [Gift 1998]
    - Microfilm. Copy of 665 p. Orchestral score shelved in Flatbox 238-240., 1958, (1 box/reel (2 copies)) (Box 40X)
      [Gift 1987 and 1990. ]
    - Record: "William Wyler's: The Big Country.", 1958, (1 disc) (Box 42)
      [See also compact disc (Box 43).]
    - Soundtrack. Commemorative volume with compact disc. 2 copies., 1990, (2 boxes) (Box 43)
      [Gift 1987 and 1990]
    - Tape recording. 1958, (3 boxes/reels) (Box 44)
    - Tape recording. 1987 copy of original., 1958, (3 boxes/reels) (Box 44)
    - Magnetic film transfer log. 1958, (2 pages) (Box 44)
  - Subseries III.12: Biguine
    - New Music Orchestra Series Orchestral score: 1) Published score. 2) Program (with notes): Symphony Under the Stars at Hollywood Bowl, 22-27 August 1944; 2 copies., San Fransisco, 1935 copyright; 1944., (32 pages, bd., 2 vol., bd.) (Box 11)
    - Orchestral score (6 Parts): manuscript in ink on thin sheets (incomplete)., (12 pages a.ms.) (Box 11)
    - Master score (32 Parts): published version., (95 pages) (Box 11)
      [Gift 1996]
  - Subseries III.13: Blood Wedding
    - Frederico Garcia Lorca; incidental music by Moross. Vocal score: 1) Manuscript in pencil. 2) Ozalid copy. 3) Ozalid copy (incomplete). 4) Negative ozalid copy. 5) Program: New Stages Theatre, 159 Bleecker St., New York; 4 copies., 1949 (program); ca. 1950, (15 pages a.ms.s., 15 pages bd., 10 pages, 15 pages, 4 vol.) (Box 11)
  - Subseries III.14: Captive City
    - Score (film sketches): manuscript in pencil., (64 pages a.ms.) (Box 11)
    - Video tape recording: "Captive City.", (1 cassette) (Box 41)
  - Subseries III.15: Cardinal
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil. 1) "Foxtrot"; 10 p. 2) "Foxtrot"; 10 p. 3) "Waltz"; 19 p. 4) "Waltz"; 19 p., 1963, (58 pages a.ms.) (Box 241)